[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the third episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
Last time, I told you about the coordinate system.
This time with the texture uv.
In the end, I'd like to make a zoom effect like this
The process is incredibly simple.
First, load this image into GLSL.
After that, we'll treat the UV.
This is the kind of scaling process we're going to do.
So let's get to it.
Close this.
This is the TouchDesigner screen.
This is the editor screen.
First, place the GLSL TOP here
It's like this.
If you open the editor in
GLSL displayed here.
That's what it says.
This is the default for this one.
That's the part that's been commented out.
Here's how it works.
Let's comment out this one.
I'm getting an error.
What does this do?
It's called sTDInputs.
It's a function that loads the TouchDesigner texture.
If the s is a sampler and the TouchDesigner
So that means 2D is in.
As this TD is attached to it.
This is a TouchDesigner specific function
This is loading the texture uv.
in the form of
Let's actually load the image
Movie File In.
Like this.
Or a banana, for that matter.
I'd like to use this image of a flower this time.
Like this.
It's listed as 1280x720.
If you put this in this #1 spot.
This one starts with a zero, so 0, 1, 2 and so on.
And this corresponds to a zero here.
Put this on.
Automatically, this 1280x720 pixel
I joined this GLSL.
Just like we did last time.
What values are in the uv?
I'd like to see it.
That's a zero and a one.
Like this.
If you do this, there's an xy in here and
If x is 0 to 1
If y is 0 to 1 and
and this is the value of 1, 1
I'll just comment on this one again, and then I'll do this
Image.
I'm going to scale this up and down.
You will have to deal with the uv value
Using the variable
This is so much more than just a position.
I don't care what it is.
We'll use this uv value
This is like the same number that's in there now with the p in it.
The vUV.st and this p
Here's what it would look like if we multiply it by 2
It's going to get bigger because of my "Hangover 2".
It's the other way around.
On the other hand, try multiplying it by 0.5 or something like that.
It's getting bigger.
It's like this.
Let's go back to two again to see what's going on.
I'd like to take a look at it.
I'll go back to the uv display here one more time.
So this is how it's going to be.
I'll have to put this p in here.
This is what it looks like when you put a p in
I think it's a little weird.
In short, this time it was 0 to 1 before.
So it's a 0 to 2 thing.
I'm doubling it here.
Values from 0 to 1 can be found here
This is the place.
Like this.
So here it's 0,0 and here it's actually 2,2.
So here's the one and one.
So there's an image in here that has a value of 0 to 1.
And this is how it goes.
If you look at this in TOP To.
It's like this.
TOP To is by default this middle
I'm taking values around here.
At this point, the r's going to be one.
You can see from here that it's not going to change in one like this
x.
So everything from here to here is the same.
This is what you get when you make it a 4 or something.
We're one here, and the rest will be the same from here.
And this is how it goes.
Let's just leave it at that.
I'll bring it back.
Like this.
Input Extended Mode UV for GLSL options
It's called
It defaults to zero.
Here's what it's all about.
A value other than 0 to 1
When the value is less than 0 and greater than 1
It's about how to handle it.
When it's Zero, it doesn't do anything. If you set it to Hold.
You know, the kind that shows these edge pixels as they are.
When you go gurgling to the right and stretching upward and upward
It's like this.
There's more variety, so here it is.
If you use "Repeat", you can get a repetition like this
I'll call it Mirror.
It's supposed to be displayed in reverse like this.
I think I'll leave it at Repeat.
Here's what it looks like.
Now, here in the variable that's now 2.
I'd like to include a uniform variable so that I can control it externally
Use this.
uniform float
This time, I'm letting him Repeat.
Let's make it a variable called uRepeat
If you put this uRepeat in here
This way, it's a little
I got a warning.
Since uniform uRepeat is showing as unassigned
this time
I couldn't do it last time, but if I press this button.
You got in here automatically.
It's 0.5, so it's twice as big as the other way around.
I'm going to make this one here.
If you set it to 2, this is what it looks like.
Now let's put some numbers in here.
I want to make a little animation.
First, LFO.
I'm going to ramp the LFO.
I don't care what it is.
Put a Math CHOP in here.
If you put a null at the end, you can add
It's a bit of a mess, so we'll move on.
Like this.
It's a 0 to 1 value here.
Let's make this place from 0 to 3, for example.
If you do this, this uRepeat will be set to a value between 0 and 3
That's what it looks like.
It came out this way.
I'm feeling a little busy.
Turn down the frequency a bit.
Let's keep it at about 0.5.
At this rate, yes.
The bottom left corner is animated with the standard.
I'd like to take this to the middle.
Just to make it clear once.
I'd like to turn this Repeat off and turn it into Zero.
Also, I was thinking of stopping the animation one more time.
We have to stop this.
I can't stop.
If you make this one, one, it's always one.
We can't keep going back to one.
I put it on two all the way.
It's in this state.
I'd like you to zoom in on that, more or less.
Let me stop you right there for a moment.
How do we do this?
I'm going to change the code around here a bit.
p
Once I split this code into two parts.
So here's what we're going to do.
Once we take this reference point up a bit.
Minus 0.5
Take it upstairs once.
Now I'm going to take it to the bottom left corner.
This way, it will move in the middle like this.
I'm going to put this repeat of what I did earlier again.
When it comes to things like this.
I'd like to move it around a bit more.
Back to 0-3 again.
This is what the animation looks like.
If you set the repeat value here to, say, Hold, you'll get
Yes.
And this is what it looks like when you set it to Hold or something.
When I zeroed in on it, there was nothing.
This is how it works with Mirror
I made one of these.
You may have already noticed this.
This process.
You can do the exact same thing with Transform TOP.
I'm getting a Transform TOP error.
I put this in here, and it goes like this.
Here at Scale.
I'll use the uRepeat which is included here
Like this.
So this is the opposite of what you're doing.
This is just the opposite of what we're doing.
I can break it up for you like this and you'll get the same movement.
I saw it here earlier on GLSL.
What was it again?
Input Extended Mode There is something similar to UV
It works exactly the same way.
You can get this in by selecting Repeat here
In this case, this pivot was originally set to 0.5.
It's designed to work in the middle reference.
If this is set to 0, the previous
It's going to be animated like a state.
Here.
This is how the TOP of TouchDesigner looks like
So it's mostly made of GLSL's wrapper.
Basically, if you use these things as they are.
It's not a problem.
If it's a situation that's pretty much a performance concern, or
If it was a serious situation.
That's more than using a lot of these TOPs.
It's better to write them all together in one GLSL.
You can improve your performance.
So I know that this is what you can do.
I think there's no harm in that.
Of course, if it was any other software in TouchDesigner
I can't use Transform TOP or anything like that.
I think this kind of knowledge would be useful.
There's a lot of stuff on the top.
Like Kinect or Nvidia Flex, for example.
This kind of thing is already a built-in SDK.
I can't really write quickly on GLSL for a moment.
For example, like this Add or Circle.
These are pretty easy to make.
After doing some effects, we're going to do some Procedual Drawing.
It's like this geometric animation.
I'd like to make a simple animation in GLSL, so I'm going to
I don't know how many times this is going to happen.
If you're interested, I hope to see you again then.
That's it.
In addition to the YouTube tutorials on TDSW
We offer live streaming workshops about two weekends a month.
If you are interested in TDSW through the tutorial
Please come and visit us at our live streaming workshops!
Also, TDSW uses Patreon
Currently, the YouTube Tutorial Creation Support Plan
Workshop Video Plan
Workshop Videos and Live Streaming Video Plan
There are three plans available
It is more profitable than attending the workshop by itself.
I hope you will consider it.
You can find these links in the overview section, so please check them out!
So thank you for watching.
Please subscribe to the channel if you'd like.
goodbye
[Music]